EMRE ÇOLAK

Mechanical Engineer | Business Development | Node.js & Vue.js Developer



+90 505 997 91 61 colakkemre@gmail.com

Ortahisar / TRABZON



GitHub emrecolak-23



Medium @colakkemre

Skills

Javascript TypeScript Node.Js Vue.js React.js

Redux

MongoDB

Redis

Express.js

Nest.js

Bootstrap

HTML

CSS

Swift

XCode

Laravel

Php

Profile

In 2009, I got into Yıldız Technical University. I studied Mechanical Engineering and selected The department of Thermodynamics and Heat in Mechanical Engineering at end of second years in University. My avarage point score was 3.19 at end of the University, I worked as mechanical, automotive and automatisation engineer at several company. For three years, I have dedicated towards web and mobile app development such as Swift, Node.js, Vue.js, React Native. Also I am a member of patika.dev and kodla.co

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Wears, 2022-

- Build web application that profiles the advanced features of React, Redux, Express, and Mongo, Vue, Lambda function.
- Build a Client-Side Rendered React and Vue App to render data from node micro services.
- Deploy web app to the cloud with Docker and Kubernetes.
- · Create CI/CD pipeline.
- Use Tensorflow and Pose Estimation pre-made model to create smart web cam app with vue.is.
- Create communication data between services using a lightningfast event bus and image process side

Full Stack Developer, Eneftimbu 2021-2022

- Build a Server-Side Rendered React App to render data from node micro services
- · Responsible for integrating smart contract on system

Logo Cyber Security Full Stack Bootcamp offered by Patika.dev, 2021

Responsible for programming backend with node.js and frontend with vue.js

Project Specialist & Coordinator, Trabzon Teknokent, Trabzon — 2019-2022

- Responsible for designing emails, coding, and testing them from start to finish
- Provide support to all company in order to promote their goods, products and service.
- Contributing to universities and educational hub for playing critical role interacting with the business community

Dynometer Test And Calibration Engineer, Ford Motor Company, Kocaeli — 2015-2019

Received Recognition Award from Ford Motor Company

- Responsible for Engine testing development at calibration project
- Responsible for providing support to advanced planning and processes to ensure that engine and all testing equipment is available
- Responsible for the creation and management of instructions for engine installation and removal, testing, daily checks, servicing and rework
- Responsible for progression of test cell and engine mechanical issues
- Responsible for monitoring communication and tracking of engine mechanical defects and failures via processes, ensuring failed components are available for development team

Technical Sales Engineer, Işık Endüstriyel, İstanbul — 2014-2015

- Responsible for supporting facility engineers to make a business plan on steam equipments maintenance management, such as those using superheated steam, turbines, valve
- Responsible for checking equipment whether steam leakage or blockage
- · Completed management internship

Education

Yıldız Technical University, Mechanical Engineer — 3.17, 2014 Anatolian University, Web Design And Coding — 3.84, 2020

Projects

Size-Estimated App

In this project, I build a massive human size estimated app leveraging with Vue.js, Node.js, Tensorflow.js, MongoDb

Live Link: https://www.ozdilekteyim.com/magaza/first-company-erkektisort-2210101507-p-12707244

Vue-Ecommerce Product Detailed Page

In this project, I build web app leveraging with Vue.js and Node.js

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/vue-ecommerce-

Live Link: https://blue-sand-0698dbf10.2.azurestaticapps.net/cream-jacket

React-Ecommerce App

In this project, I build a massive E-commerce app leveraging with Redux, Hooks, GraphQL, Stripe, Firebase.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/react-ecommerce Live Link: https://main--amazing-stardust-b17fa1.netlify.app/

Full Stack App

In this project, I build and deploy fullstack web apps with NodeJS, React, Redux, Express, and MongoDB.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/full-stack-react-node

Asana Clone

In this project, I cloned the backend of the asana platform. I used node.js for the backend. I used the express.js package for the rest api architecture. I used mongodb as a no sql database. I used npm packages such as joi for validation, winston for logging, and Jwt for token generation.

Ecommerce App

In this study, I developed Ecommerce web site. I used Vue.js on front-end and Node.js on backend. I created my own api with Express.js and performed the CRUD operations of the products through this api. I used jwt and bcrypt packages for registration and login process. I used both Elasticsearch and PostgreSQL as database. I used the query structure of elasticsearch to search for products in the application.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/ecommerceApp

MisFit WebApp

In this project, I developed web app. I benefit from prepared html template for frontend. I used Node.js on backend. Also I used some node packages such as

express.js, express-session, multer, nodemailer, joi, winston, connect-flash, bcrypt, slugify. This app has three user role such as admin, trainer and member. These user roles has their own dashboard view. In this app I select mongoDB as a database. I used mongoose ORM to connect Mongo DB

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/misFit

Heroku Link: https://misfitness-app.herokuapp.com

Education App

In this study, I developed Education web site. I used Node.js for backend. This app has two user role such as teacher and student. Also, this app has course, user and category model. In dashboard view, admin can add or delete this models. I used MongoDB in this project. I use mongoose ORM to connect MongoDB.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/SmartEdu

Heroku Link: https://smart-eduapp.herokuapp.com

Blog Site Node.JS Development

In this project, I create blog web app with node.js. In this project I use express module of nodejs. I use ejs to make dynamic web-site on frontend.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/cleanBlogNode

Heroku Link: https://dashboard.heroku.com/apps/blog-techno

Photo Blog WebApp Node.JS Development

In this project, I developed photo blog web app with node.js. In this project I use express module of node.js. I use ejs to make dynamic web-site on frontend.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/PCAT

Heroku Link: https://pcat-photo.herokuapp.com

Portfolio App

In this project, I developed web app with node.js. I developed a portfolio application. So that users can upload their work to app. I benefit from some modules in node.js such as express.js, express-session, multer. Besides I select mongoDB as a database. I use mongoose ORM to connect mongoDB

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/agencyApp

Heroku Link: https://portfolio-app-ec.herokuapp.com

OBD Monitor, Oca 2017 - Oca 2018

In this study, I write matlab code observing engine when it run in the test cell. This code is called OBD Monitor. It comprehend the meaning of the failure code relating to engine parameters. It also give operator information about why this failure code appear. If possible, It may take action automatically without human interference.

The Effect of Charge Air and Fuel Injection Parameters on Combustion Oca 2017 - Oca 2018

The aim of this study is to observe engine reaction when engine parameters are changed. At the end of this study, Internal combustion engine is modeled through Matlab scripts.

BMI Calculator iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I create a iOS app to calculate users BMI.

Basic React Native App Development

In this project, I develop a app using react native. In this app, I create user login and register page. I can keep users state information with firebase. I create tab menu and users can tap tab menu item. When they tap, app get dummy post, todolist and users json data from http://JSOnplaceholder.typicode.com

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/ReactNativeApp

BitCoin App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I make a Bitcoin price ticker. The app give the latest Bitcoin price. I use URLSession to make HTTP request and JSON Decoder for JSON parsing.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/ByteCoin-iOS14

Calculator iOS Mobile App

In this project, I used stack views in swift programming language. I created complex layout. This app run like a calculator.

Chat App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I use firebase firestore database, cocoapods package manage and UITableView.

Dicee App iOS Mobile app Development

In this project, I work on ARKit & Augment Reality in swift.

Github Link: https://github.com/emrecolak-23/ARDiceApp

Flower Recognition App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I use CoreML in order to use a ready-made plug and play mlmodel. And I perform image recognition by adding it. I convert a pre trained caffe model. And finally app get information about your cameras view and merge some kind of flower and show Wikipedia result.

News App iOS Mobile app Development

In this project, I identify protocol and use networking in swiftUI. Also, I benefit observer design pattern.

Projects Portal

In this project, I created user login and management system in larval 8. And the user role of entrepreneurs fill form. System send forms data SQL Database and other role of user read the data which entrepreneurs write.

Quizz App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I used structures, methods and properties in swift. This app show questions and check whether users answer is true or false.

Reastaurant Menu Javascript

In this project, I create a one page with html, css and javascript. In this Web app, I show restaurant menu based on category.

Sound App iOS Mobile app Development

In this project, I create iOS mobile app. In this app when users tap the buttons on the screen, they can play different sounds.

Todo App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I use core data with a sequel like back in database. I create a relational database as backend and code up to front end.

Weather App iOS Mobile App Development

In this project, I used networking, JSON Parsing, API's and Core Location.

Sertification

Logo Siber Güvenlik Full Stack Bootcamp offered by Patika

iOS&Swift - The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp Udemy

KOSGEB Girişimcilik Eğitimi KOSGEB

Codeigniter 4

UdemyUdemy

CCPMP02-Project Management with PMP* Standarts and PMP* Certification Exam Preparation

İzge Eğitim ve Danışmanlık İzge Eğitim ve Danışmanlık

Teknoloji Geliştirme Bölgeleri Mevzuatı ve Bölge Süreçleri TGBD AkademiTGBD Akademi

ISO 27001 : Information Security Management System iema Eğitim & Danışmanlık Eğitim & Danışmanlık

ISO 31001: Risk Management System

iema Eğitim & Danışmanlıkiema Eğitim & Danışmanlık

ISO 9001: Quality Management System iema Eğitim & Danışmanlıkiema Eğitim & Danışmanlık

Profesyonel Hayatta Pozitif Etki ve Kişisel İmaj Ford OtosanFord Otosan

Commercialization

VivekaViveka

Product Marketing

VivekaViveka

Tasarım Odaklı Düşünme

Makers Türkiye Makers Türkiye

Pozitif Psikoloji ile Motivasyon ve Odaklanma

Pulse Consulting ClinicPulse Consulting Clinic

6 Sigma Green Belt

Ford OtosanFord Otosan

SolidWorks

Üçüncü Binyıl AkademiÜçüncü Binyıl Akademi

Vba Application

BilgeAdam TeknolojiBilgeAdam Teknoloji